# Mauricio Vásquez Bernal

Software Engineer Research Assistant Polytechnic University of Turin



Aug 31, 1991



mauriciovasquezbernal@gmail.com



mauriciovasquezbernal.github.io



Medellín - Colombia

# Languages

Spanish Italian





# Skills -

### **Programming Languages**

С C++ Go Python Java • • • •

### Computer Networks

eBPF and XDP TCP/IP SDN and NFV

### Virtualization

KVM/QEMU Open vSwitch Docker & LXC

Kubernetes

0 0 OpenStack 0 0 0

#### Software Development

Git Open Source **GDB** 

# Soft Skills -

**Problem Solving** Self-Motivation Communication Teamwork

### **Profile**

Young software engineer with 3+ years of experience in developing software. I am a proactive team member, very motivated and enthusiast about new life challenges. I am one of the main developers of Polycube, an open source framework for developing virtual network functions with eBPF and XDP. I play nicely with open source development, I have contributed to different projects like Linux kernel, BPF Compiler Collection (BCC), Open vSwitch (OVS) and Data Plane Development Kit (DPDK).

### **Experience**

Feb 2016 -

#### **Research Assistant**

Polytechnic University of Turin

Present

 Developing of polycube, an open source framework to build fast and lightweight virtual network functions witheBPF

• Developing of high-performance virtual network functions with eBPF and XDP

Contributing to open source projects like Linux kernel and BCC

Feb 2015 -May 2017

Consultant

Nebbiolo Technologies • Implementing high performant virtual network functions with eBPF

Sep 2016 -

Plumgrid (Acquired by VMware)

Jan 2017

• Developing iovisor-ovn, an eBPF datapath for Open Virtual Networking (OVN)

Jan 2015 -Aug 2016

**Research Assistant** 

Polytechnic University of Turin

• Developing of a high-performance communication channel for inter-VM communication in Open vSwitch

• Contributing to open source projects like Open vSwitch (OvS) and Dataplane Development Kit (DPDK)

Participating in the Unify European Project

### **Education**

2013 - 2015 Master in Computer Engineering Polytechnic University of Turin 2009 – 2013 Bachelor in Electronic Engineering University of Antioquia

### **Projects**

#### **Polycube**

github.com/polycube-network/polycube

Polycube is an open source framework for developing fast and lightweight network functions using eBPF and XDP.

### IOVisor-ovn

github.com/iovisor/iovisor-ovn

IOVisor-ovn is an eBPF based datapath for the Open Virtual Networking project. It provides a virtual networking solution for virtual machines in environments like Open Stack.

### **Squadra Corse Polito**

facebook.com/pg/SCPolito

Squadra Corse is a student racing team from Polytechnic University of Turin. Each year the team design, build and test an electric car to compete against teams from other universities all around the world. I was in charge of developing the telemetry and datalogging systems.

# **Publications**

Jun 2018 Creating Complex Network Services with eBPF: Experience and **Lessons Learned** 

Oct 2018 Transparent Optimization of Inter-Virtual Network Function Communication in Open vSwitch

CloudNet

A Transparent Highway for inter-Virtual Network Function Com-Aug 2016 munication with Open vSwitch

SIGCOMM

May 3, 2019

**Mauricio Vásquez Bernal**